KiBot.
Yeah,
yeah, it's getting pretty popular.
A lot of people use it.
Oh, tell me about it.
So much clicking.
Yeah, it can really be a game changer, especially if you're doing, like, any
kind of serious design work.
Well, the main thing is it handles all those essential manufacturing files,
like Gerber files.
So Gerber files are basically like, think of them as blueprints, but for
your circuit board, you send those to the manufacturer, and that's what they
use to actually print the circuit board.
Exactly. It's a huge time saver.
And honestly, it just kind of takes away that possibility for human error.
Because we all know you stare at those circuit boards long enough, you're
bound to mess something up.
Right.
For sure.
Right. And that's where those design rule checks come in.
The ERC and DRC.
Pretty much, it goes through and looks for common errors, any kind of
violations. And it really just makes sure your design is, you know, solid
and actually manufacturable.
Yeah, I feel that it's a lot, especially when you're in the zone for hours.
Well, it can do documentation, too.
Yeah, like your bills of materials.
You know, those lists of every component you need? KiBot generates those
for you.
Yeah, it even gives you cost estimation.
So you're not, like, stuck trying to wrangle a spreadsheet at two in the
morning.
Exactly. It's super helpful, whether you're, you know, just doing this as a
hobby or you're running a whole business.
Wait, there's more? Yeah, we haven't even gotten to one of the coolest parts
yet. Ki bot also does 3d modeling.
Yeah. Like really high quality 3d models of your boards using blender.
Yeah, it's seriously cool stuff.
Well, KiBot basically takes your KCAD designs, right? And then it
transforms them into these, like, really detailed 3D Models.
No, no, no, not at all.
Like, it shows you the components, the placements, you know, all the
details, even down to, like, the surface finishes.
It's pretty impressive.
Yeah.
Well, first off, just visualizing the design.
You're not stuck with these, like, flat schematics anymore.
You can actually see how it all fits together in 3d space.
Yeah, it makes it way easier to spot any potential issues, like, you know,
something's too close together or just to get a feel for the layout, you
know? Totally.
And it's not just for the designer either.
You can use these 3d models for presentations, marketing materials, stuff
like that.
Oh, for sure.
And what's cool is because it uses blender, which is like a really powerful
3d modeling software.
You're not just limited to viewing it, you can actually export it in
different formats and use it with other tools.
Exactly. Well, let's say you're working with like, mechanical engineers and
they're designing the enclosure for your board.
You can export the KiBot model and send it to them, and they can actually
use it in their CAD software.
Yep, exactly.
No more back and forth trying to describe everything over email
for sure.
Or, you know, even if you just want to run some simulations, like see how
your board is going to perform under different conditions, you can use those
models for that too.
Exactly. And this kind of 3d integration, it's not something you see in a
lot of free and open source tools.
It's really pretty remarkable what they're doing with KiBotan.
Oh, yeah, it's a lifesaver.
So imagine this, you have your base circuit board design, right?
Exactly. And instead of having to create like, separate files for each
version, KiBot lets you manage all those variations within the same
project. Yep.
You basically set up parameters, right, and different options for things.
So for your wireless module, let's say it comes in Bluetooth, wifi and
cellular, you tell KiBot, hey, this component could be any of these.
It's kind of like having a dropdown menu right there in your design.
Yeah. New.
When you're ready to generate your output files, you just choose which
variant you want.
KiBot does the rest.
Absolutely. You get the correct boom, assembly drawings, everything for
whichever variation you choose.
So no more second guessing if you're looking at the right files.
Exactly. And this isn't just for, like, small tweaks we're talking.
You can even create completely different products from that same core
design.
Exactly. Think of the design, reuse, the time and money you save.
KiBot really bringing these high end features to everyone, which is
incredible.
Yeah, it's really remarkable what they've managed to put together.
Exactly. There's a whole community of developers constantly adding new
features and making it even better.
Well, it's hard to say for sure, but I think it's part of this larger trend.
You know, these really powerful design tools are becoming accessible to
everyone. So as it evolves, I think KiBot has the potential to, you know,
just make advanced electronics design, something anyone can do, not just big
companies with big budgets.
I totally agree.
It's definitely worth checking out.