Okay, so today we're diving into this really cool tool I found.
It's called KiBot, and it's designed to work with KiCad.
I'm sure a lot of our listeners have heard of it, maybe even use it.
It's that free and open source electronics design software.
Yeah, exactly.
So if anyone out there listening is tired of those tedious tasks, you know,
like all the boring stuff you have to do when you're designing electronic.
Right? That's what KiBot is supposed to be, like, your new best friend.
Okay, so walk me through it from the beginning.
What kinds of tasks does KiBot automate?
Okay. Kerber files.
Yeah, but for people who don't know, what are those?
So instead of me having to go and figure out all the settings every single
time, KiBot takes care of all that.
Oh, yeah, for sure.
Been there, done that.
Not fun.
So it's definitely saving us from some late night manufacturing panic
attacks. Okay, so that's one less thing to worry about.
But what about catching those errors before we even get to that stage? Like,
during the actual design process?
It's like having someone looking over your shoulder, double checking your
work.
That's a relief.
Sometimes my brain just can't even handle another schematic.
Okay, so we've covered the manufacturing files and the error checking.
What else can this thing do? Documentation.
Really?
Oh, wow.
Okay, so it's like it's helping with the budget too.
That's actually amazing.
Right? That makes sense.
Wow. Okay, so far, KiBot is blowing my mind a little bit.
Oh, there's more
3d modeling.
Okay, now that I'm really interested in.
Okay, so before the break, you kind of blew my mind a little bit.
Talking about 3d modeling, I'm really curious about this.
So tell me, how does it actually work?
Okay, so we're not talking about just like, a basic 3d block here.
Wow, that's amazing.
What are the advantages of having, you know, like, a super high quality 3d
model like that?
Right. That makes a lot of sense.
Right. Especially with more complex boards.
That could be really helpful.
Yeah, definitely.
I mean, everyone loves a good 3d render.
It's way more exciting than just looking at, like, a 2d drawing.
Oh, okay.
So you could take the model from KiBotan and use it in a completely
different program.
So, like, give me an example.
How would you use that?
Oh, so they can make sure it fits properly and everything.
That's huge, because those design clashes can be a real pain.
Wow. It's like you're giving your design a virtual test run before you even
like solder anything.
It's very, very cool.
Okay, so we talked about the 3d modeling, but there's one more thing that I
really wanted to ask you about, and that's the product variants.
I've definitely worked on projects where, like, we needed a few different
versions of the same board, and it's always a bit of a headache to manage.
So before the break, we were talking about product variants, and I got to
say, for someone like me who hates juggling a million different files, this
sounds like a dream come true.
So how does KiBot make it so easy to handle all these different variations?
But you need a few different versions, just with little tweaks here and
there, right? Like maybe one needs a different connector or are you swapping
out a wireless module or something?
Oh, wow.
So it's all in one place,
so you don't have to go back and like, manually swap out components every
time you need a different version.
That is so much slicker than the way I've been doing it.
And what about the documentation? Does it handle that for each variant too?
Okay, seriously, that's amazing.
Especially for like, bigger projects that could save so much time and
confusion. It's like KiBot just brings order to the chaos.
Oh, wow.
So you could have one base design that's like a platform for a whole product
line.
It's amazing how much you could do with this one tool.
Honestly, we've covered so much automating all those tedious tasks, creating
amazing 3d models, and now managing all these product variants.
Kibot sounds like it has everything covered.
The coolest part is it's open source.
Right? So it's constantly evolving, always getting better.
That's what I love about open source.
So, any predictions for the future of Kibot? Where do you see it going?
That is such an exciting thought.
Who knows what incredible inventions people will come up with when they have
these kinds of tools at their fingertips? Well, I have to say, this deep
dive into KiBot has been really eye opening.
I think it's an amazing resource for anyone.
Whether you're just getting started with electronics or you're a seasoned
pro, you.
And for anyone listening who's feeling inspired, you can find links to
everything we talked about today in the show notes.
So be sure to check it out and let us know what you think.
Until next time.