Okay, so today we're diving into this really cool tool I found.
It's called KiBot.
KiBot? Yeah, and it's designed to work with KiCad.
I'm sure a lot of our listeners have heard of it, maybe even use it.
It's that free and open source electronics design software.
Yeah, it's getting pretty popular.
A lot of people use it.
Yeah, exactly.
So if anyone out there listening is tired of those tedious tasks, you know,
like all the boring stuff you have to do when you're designing electronics.
Oh, tell me about it.
So much clicking right, that's what KiBot is supposed to be like, your new
best friend.
Yeah, it can really be a game changer, especially if you're doing any kind
of serious design work.
Okay, so walk me through it from the beginning.
What kinds of tasks does KiBot automate? Well, the main thing is it handles
all those essential manufacturing files.
Like Gerber files.
Okay, Gerber files.
Yeah, but for people who don't know, what are those? So Gerber files are
basically like, think of them as blueprints, but for your circuit board, you
send those to the manufacturer, and that's what they use to actually print
the circuit board.
So instead of me having to go and figure out all the settings every single
time, KiBot takes care of all that.
Exactly. It's a huge time saver.
And honestly, it just kind of takes away that possibility for human error.
Because we all know you stare at those circuit boards long enough, you're
bound to mess something up, right? Oh, yeah, for sure.
Been there, done that.
Not fun.
So it's definitely saving us from some late night manufacturing panic
attacks, for sure.
Okay, so that's one less thing to worry about.
But what about catching those errors before we even get to that stage? Like
during the actual design process? Right, and that's where those design rule
checks come in, the ERC and DRC.
It's like having someone looking over your shoulder, double checking your
work. Pretty much.
It goes through and looks for common errors, any kind of violations, and it
really just makes sure your design is, you know, solid and actually
manufacturable. That's a relief.
Sometimes my brain just can't even handle another schematic.
I feel that it's a lot, especially when you're in the zone for hours.
Okay, so we've covered the manufacturing files and the error checking.
What else can this thing do? Well, it can do documentation, too.
Documentation, really? Yeah, like your bills of materials.
You know, those lists of every component you need? KiBot generates those
for you.
Oh, wow.
Yeah. It even gives you cost estimation, so you're not stuck trying to
wrangle a spreadsheet at two in the morning.
Okay. So it's like it's helping with the budget too.
That's actually amazing.
Exactly. It's super helpful whether you're just doing this as a hobby or
you're running a whole business.
Right. That makes sense.
Wow. Okay, so far, kibot is blowing my mind a little bit.
Wait, there's more.
Oh, there's more? Yeah.
We haven't even gotten to one of the coolest parts yet.
Ki bot also does 3d modeling.
3d modeling? Yeah, like, really high quality 3d models of your boards using
blender. Okay, now that I'm really interested in.
Okay, so before the break, you kind of blew my mind a little bit.
Talking about 3d modeling, I'm really curious about this.
Yeah, it's seriously cool stuff.
So tell me, how does it actually work? Well, ki bot basically takes your
KCAD designs, right? And then it transforms them into these, like, really
detailed 3d models.
Okay, so we're not talking about just like, a basic 3d block here.
No, no, no, not at all.
Like, it shows you the components, the placements, you know, all the
details, even down to, like, the surface finishes.
It's pretty impressive.
Wow, that's amazing.
Yeah. What are the advantages of having, like, a super high quality 3d model
like that? Well, first off, just visualizing the design.
You're not stuck with these, like, flat schematics anymore.
You can actually see how it all fits together in 3d space.
Right. That makes a lot of sense.
Yeah, it makes it way easier to spot any potential issues, like, you know,
something's too close together or just.
Just to get a feel for the layout, you know? Right.
Especially with more complex boards, that could be really helpful.
Totally. And it's not just for the designer either.
You can use these 3d models for presentations, marketing materials, stuff
like that.
Yeah, definitely.
I mean, everyone loves a good 3d render.
It's way more exciting than just looking at, like, a 2d drawing.
Oh, for sure.
And what's cool is because it uses blender, which is like a really powerful
3d modeling software.
You're not just limited to viewing it.
You can actually export it in different formats and use it with other tools.
Oh, okay.
So you could take the model from KiBot and use it in a completely
different program.
Exactly. So, like, give me an example.
How would you use that? Well, let's say you're working with, like,
mechanical engineers and they're designing the enclosure for your board.
You can export the KiBot model and send it to them and they can actually
use it in their cad software.
Oh, so they can make sure it fits properly and everything? Yep, exactly.
No more back and forth trying to describe everything over email.
That's huge, because those design clashes can be a real pain for sure.
Or even if you just want to run some simulations, see how your board's going
to perform under different conditions, you can use those models for that
too. Wow, it's like you're giving your design a virtual test run before you
even solder anything.
Exactly. And this kind of 3d integration, it's not something you see in a
lot of free and open source tools.
It's really pretty remarkable what they're doing with KiBot.
It's very, very cool.
Okay, so we talked about the 3d modeling, but there's one more thing that I
really wanted to ask you about, and that's the product variants.
I've definitely worked on projects where like, we needed a few different
versions of the same board, and it's always a bit of a headache to manage.
So before the break we were talking about product variants, and I gotta say,
for someone like me who hates juggling a million different files, this
sounds like a dream come true.
Oh yeah, it's a lifesaver.
So how does KiBot make it so easy to handle all these different
variations? So imagine this, you have your base circuit board design, right?
But you need a few different versions, just with little tweaks here and
there, right? Like maybe one needs a different connector or are you swapping
out a wireless module or something? Exactly.
And instead of having to create like separate files for each version, KiBot
lets you manage all those variations within the same project.
Oh wow, so it's all in one place.
Yep. You basically set up parameters, right, and different options for
things. So for your wireless module, let's say it comes in bluetooth, wifi
and cellular.
You tell KiBot, hey, this component could be any of these.
It's kind of like having a dropdown menu right there in your design so you
don't have to go back and like manually swap out components every time you
need a different version.
Yeah. New.
When you're ready to generate your output files, you just choose which
variant you want, KiBot does the rest.
That is so much slicker than the way I've been doing it.
And what about the documentation, does it handle that for each variant too?
Absolutely. You get the correct boom, assembly drawings, everything for
whichever variation you choose.
So no more second guessing if you're looking at the right files.
Okay, seriously, that's amazing.
Especially for, like, bigger projects that could save so much time and
confusion. It's like KiBot just brings order to the chaos.
Exactly. And this isn't just for, like, small tweaks.
We're talking.
You can even create completely different products from that same core
design. Oh, wow.
So you could have one base design that's like a platform for a whole product
line. Exactly.
Think of the design, reuse the time and money you save.
KiBot really bringing these high end features to everyone, which is
incredible. It's amazing how much you could do with this one tool, honestly.
We've covered so much automating, all those tedious tasks, creating amazing
3d models, and now managing all these product variants.
Kibot sounds like it has everything covered.
Yeah, it's really remarkable what they've managed to put together.
The coolest part is it's open source.
Right. So it's constantly evolving, always getting better.
Exactly. There's a whole community of developers constantly adding new
features and making it even better.
That's what I love about open source.
So, any predictions for the future of Kibot? Where do you see it going?
Well, it's hard to say for sure, but I think it's part of this larger trend.
You know, these really powerful design tools are becoming accessible to
everyone. So as it evolves, I think KiBot has the potential to, you know,
just make advanced electronics design something anyone can do, not just big
companies with big budgets.
That is such an exciting thought.
Who knows what incredible inventions people will come up with when they have
these kinds of tools at their fingertips? Well, I have to say, this deep
dive into KiBot has been really eye opening.
I think it's an amazing resource for anyone.
Whether you're just getting started with electronics or you're a seasoned
pro, I totally agree.
It's definitely worth checking out.
And for anyone listening who's feeling inspired, you can find links to
everything we talked about today in the show notes, so be sure to check it
out and let us know what you think.
Until next time.