[Music]
In the realm where circuits dance,
With KiCad's grace, we take a chance.
Through tangled wires and schematics bright,
A world of dreams ignites the night.
O KiBot, guardian of the code,
With every task, our burdens unload.
In silence you weave, the files we require,
A symphony of circuits, you inspire!
No more chaos, no more despair,
With every commit, you're always there.
Reproducible paths, so clear and precise,
In Docker's embrace, we find paradise.
O KiBot, guardian of the code,
With every task, our burdens unload.
In silence you weave, the files we require,
A symphony of circuits, you inspire!
No more chaos, no more despair,
With every commit, you're always there.
Reproducible paths, so clear and precise,
In Docker's embrace, we find paradise.
O KiBot, guardian of the code,
With every task, our burdens unload.
In silence you weave, the files we require,
A symphony of circuits, you inspire!
From GitHub to GitLab, our voices unite,
In harmony forged, we conquer the night.
Errors erased, our visions align,
With KiBot beside us, our futures will shine.
O KiBot, forever we'll sing,
Of the freedom and joy that you bring.
In the world of design, your legacy grows,
A master of rhythm, where innovation flows!
[Music]