[Music]
in the real where Ser dance with King
cat's Grace we take a
chance so tangle wires and schematic
Sprite a world of Dreams ignites the
night oh c a guardian of the CR with
every task the burn
Al inside you we the files we require a
symphony of circuits you
inspire no more chaos no more despair
with every commit you're always
there we produce the both paths so clear
and precise in Do's Embrace we find
Paradise all time by guardian of the
cold with every task our burdens un low
in sign you we the files we require a
symphony of circuits you
inspire no more chaos no more despair
with every commit you're always there
reproducible path so clear and precise
in darkers Embrace we find Paradise all
C and all the code with every task our
burdens un L it silence you we the FES
we require a symphony of circuits you
inspire from GI H to get laugh void
voices unite in harmony forged we
conquer the night erors erased our
Visions align with kba beside us our
futures will
shine oh forever will sing of the
freedom and joy that you bring in the
world of design your legacy grows a
master true Rhythm where Innovation
[Music]
flows e